感觉不堪重负
Can't get the monkey off your back?
那就来一杯
Then put it in your mouth...
猴子乐啤酒
...With MonkeyShine Beer.
MonkeyShine Beer,
尽享自在生活
'cause it's a jungle out there.
那支广告总让我悲从中来
That commercial always makes me so sad.
但是那个家伙一开啤酒  女人就拥上来了
Yeah, but then the guy opens his beer and those girls run at him,
所以结果还是不错的
so, everything seems to work out OK.
那只猴子让我想到了马塞尔
I meant because the monkey in it reminds me of Marcel.
我看得出来
I can see that,
它们都有棕色的大眼睛  还有鼓鼓的小下巴
'cause they both have those big brown eyes and, ya know, the little pouty chin.
而且它们都是猴子
And the fact that they're both monkeys.
有时我怀疑  我把它送走是对还是错
Sometimes I wonder if I did the right thing, ya know, giving him away.
罗斯  你也是迫不得已  他看到什么都要去拨弄
Oh, Ross, you had to, I mean, he was humping everything in sight.
我的马里布芭比结婚都穿不上穿白纱了
I mean, I have a Malibu Barbi who will no longer be wearing white to her wedding.
记得有时它会跟你借帽子
Remember when sometimes he'd borrow your hat,
等你要回来的时候  里面会有几粒猴葡萄干
and, and when you got it back there'd be little monkey raisins in it.
它干的就叫好玩  换做我对我老板这么做的话
Yeah, well sure, when he did it, it was funny. When I did it to my boss's hat. . .
突然就上升到了态度问题的高度
all of the sudden I have this big attitude problem.
嘿  嘿  看嘿  猜我得到了什么嘿
Hey, hey, check it out, guess what I got.
押韵
Rhythm?
不  第一封影迷信
No, my first fan mail.
真好
Alright
"亲爱的拉莫雷医生"
"Dear Dr. Remore,..
"我爱你  为了得到你  我可以不惜一切"  天呐
know that I love you and would do anything to have you." Gosh.
"你不太神秘的仰慕者艾丽卡·福特
"Your not-so-secretive admirer, Erica Ford."
等一下
Ooh wait,
"附注  随函附上了我的十四根睫毛"
"PS enclosed please find 14 of my eyelashes."
在疯子的世界里  那就表示你结婚了
Ya know, in crazy world, that means you're married.
这不是寄到剧组的  是直接送到你家去的
This wasn't addressed to Days of Our Lives, this is, this came to your apartment.
信封没有盖戳  她去过我们的大楼
There's no stamp on it, this woman was in our building.
我的天
Oh my god,
我也有自己的变态影迷了
I got my very own stalker.
各位
Hey, guys.
你上哪儿去了  大忙人
Ooh, where are you off to, Travelin' Jake?
洛杉矶有一个古生物学研讨会
Well, there's this, uh, paleontology conference in L.A.
我准备去  然后开车到动物园给马塞尔一个惊喜
so I figured I'd go and then drive down to the zoo and surprise Marcel.
我想它会很惊喜的
You know I think he will be surprised,
直到它发现自己是猴子
'till he realizes he's a monkey,
根本就没法有那种情绪
and uh, you know, isn't capable of that emotion.
菲比  那个小帅哥又来了
Oh, Phoebe, that really cute guy is here again.
好  大家都假装听我在讲故事
Oh, oh, OK, so everyone, pretend like I'm telling you a story,
好  故事很好笑  所以大家要笑  快
OK. And, and it's really funny. So everyone just laugh, now.
我就知道
I know, I know.
你好
Hello.
-我叫罗伯·杜南  -你好  罗伯·杜南
- Hi. I'm Rob Dohnen. - Hi Rob Dohnen.
我对音乐一窍不通  不过我觉得你非常棒
I don't know anything about music, but I think you're really, really great.
我在替市里的儿童图书馆安排艺人的演出
Anyway, I schedule performers for the childrens libraries around the city
你有没有想过为小孩子演唱你的歌呢
and I was just thinking,have you ever thought about playing your songs for kids?
我很想要小孩
Oh, I would love to have kids. . .
你要我演唱我为他们写的歌
you're, you're the, you're, me play the songs that I will write for them.
今天晚饭怎么办
Hey, what do ya wanna do for dinner?
我们可以在家自己做
Well we could just stay in and cook for ourselves.
-谁啊  -我是艾丽卡
- Hello. - It's Erica.
变态影迷
Ah, the stalker.
不用麻烦了  门没关
Never mind, it's open.
对  用平底锅打她是个好主意
Yes, hitting her with a frying pan's a good idea.
我们还得想个备用计划  以防她不是卡通人物
We might wanna have a backup plan, though, just in case she isn't a cartoon.
快跑
Let's get out of here.
偏挑这个时候不在家
The one time they're not home.
好吧
OK,
我们就只管走  在楼梯上碰到的时候
we'll just leave, and when we pass her on the stairs,
她不会认出我  因为我们没见过
she won't know it's me 'cause we've never met.
那是电台明星的脱身方法
That's how radio stars escape stalkers.
她来了
She's comin'.
是我
It's me.
完了  我们就是这么死的
Uhh, this is it, this is how we're gonna die.
-准备好了吗  -等等
- Ready? - Wait, wait, wait.
好了
Ok.
艾丽卡
Erica.
盖勒先生
Mr. Geller?
我是迪恩·利普森  动物园管理员
Dean Lipson, zoo administrator.
听说你有问题要咨询
I was told you had a question.
我找不到我去年捐的猴子了
Well, I uh, I can't seem to find the monkey I donated last year.
它是一只戴帽猿  名叫马塞尔
He's a capuchan, answers to the name Marcel.
我恐怕有个坏消息要告诉你
Ahh, I'm afraid I have some bad news.
马塞尔已经过世了
Marcel has passed on.
天呐  怎么会呢
Oh my God, what happened?
它生病了  然后病情加重了
Well he got sick, and then he got sicker,
然后有点好转
and then he got a little better
可后来就死了
but then he died.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
请节哀  盖勒先生
I'm sorry. Mr. Geller.
可你也知道  俗话说
But ya know, there's an old saying,
"猴子难免一死"
'Sometimes monkeys die.'
不是什么精辟的俗语  但...
It's not a great saying, but...
用在当下很贴切
it certainly is fitting today.
那也应该有人通知我才对
Well, ya know, someone should have called me.
抱歉  我知道这样也不能让它起死回生
I'm sorry. Look, I know this can't bring him back
这是我一点心意  请收下
but here, it's just a gesture.
动物园礼券
Zoo dollars?
对  四点来看鸟类表演  金刚鹦鹉戴帽子
Yes, and come see the bird show at 4. The macaws wear hats.
你的猴子没死的话  表演得可爱多了
Well it's a lot cuter if your monkey hasn't just died.
我知道
I know.
真不敢相信  乔伊去跟他的变态影迷吃饭了
I can't believe Joey's having lunch with his stalker.
她长得怎么样
What i-, what is she like.
-还记得《危情十日》里的凯西·贝兹吗  -记得
- Well, you remember Cathy Bates in Misery? - Yeah.
她长得跟她恰恰相反
Well, she looks the exact opposite of that.
那她不是疯子吗
And she's not crazy?
不  她是个不折不扣的怪人
Oh no no no, she's a total wack job.
她以为乔伊真的是德雷克·拉莫雷医生
Yeah, she thinks that Joey is actually Dr. Drake Remore.
我的天
Oh my God.
然后他还要去跟她约会  他不能将错就错
Ah, and I mean, he's going out with her? He can not persue this.
就因为这个女人以为
Hey, just because this woman thinks
她可以在她家客厅的魔法盒里看到乔伊
she can actually see Joey through the magical box in her living room
并不表示她就不是个人
doesn't mean she's not a person.
她不配得到快乐  不配拥有爱吗
I mean, does she not deserve happiness, does she not deserve love?
你们看我干什么  想上那个疯子的可是乔伊
What're you lookin' at me for? He's the one who wants to boff the maniac.
你还好吧
You OK?
不  我很紧张
No, uh-uh, I'm just, I'm nervous.
如果我幻想他们只穿着内衣
So, you know what, maybe if I just, if I picture them all in their underwear.
不好  上个家伙就是那样被开除的
That's not a good idea, that's kinda the reason the last guy got fired.
我只是习惯为大人演唱
I'm just, I'm, I'm, I'm used to playing for grown-ups.
大人就只要边喝咖啡边做他们大人做的事
Ya know, they just, grown-ups drink their coffee and do their grown-up thing,
小孩呢  会专心听
ya know, and kids listen.
我觉得这个责任好重大  怎么了
This is a huge responsibility. What?
你要亲我吗
Are you gonna kiss me?
-有这个想法  -好
- I was thinkin' about it. - OK.
好吧  来点音乐吧
OK, alrighty, let's play some tunes.
-各位  我是菲比  -你好  菲比
- Hi everybody, I'm Phoebe. - Hi Phoebe.
好的
OK,
我要唱一首关于祖父母的歌
I'm gonna play, um, some songs about grandparents, OK.
奶奶人见人爱
Now, grandma's a person who everyone likes,
她给你买小火车  还送你锃亮的自行车
she bought you a train and a bright, shiny bike.
但最近她不都没来共进晚餐
But lately she hasn't been coming to dinner,
上回你看到她时  她消瘦多了
And last time you saw her she looked so much thinner.
你爸妈说她搬去了秘鲁
Now, your mom and your dad said she moved to Peru,
其实她过世了  你终有一天也会死去
but the truth is she died and some day you will too.
-德雷克  真是太好了  -是啊  没错
- Oh, Drake, isn't it amazing? - Yeah it is. . .
怎么了
what?
现在我们轻松地坐在这儿
Well, here we sit, devil may care,
但不久前  你还在重注西蒙的脊髓
just a little while ago you were reattaching Simon's spinal cord.
是啊  那手术不简单
Yeah, that was a tricky one.
实际上  那个手术要花上十几个钟头
In reality, that operation takes like, over 10 hours,
可他们只播了两分钟而已
but they only showed it for 2 minites.
"他们"是谁
Who's they?
没谁
No one.
德雷克  你真有才华  让我看看那双手
Oh Drake, you are so talented, let me see those hands.
这双美丽的手
Oh these hands, these beautiful hands,
真想吃掉它们  但是我不会
oh I could just eat them. . . but I won't.
不然我的手表一定会掉下来
Good, otherwise my watch would fall off.
不  说真的
No, seriously.
这双手  这双救人无数的神奇的手
These hands. These miracle, magical, life-giving hands.
我只要靠近抚摸  能舔一只吗
Oh, just to be near them, touch them, maybe even lick one?
好吧  一只就好了
Alright, just one.
你还挺在行
Wow, you're good at that.
天啊  来人呐  他噎住了  这里有没有医生
Oh my God! Someone, he's choking. Is anyone here a doctor?
有  有  赛伦市最好的医生就在这儿
Well, yes, yes, the best doctor in all of Salem,
德雷克·拉莫雷医生
Dr. Drake Remore.
十五分钟之后到夜行动物馆等我
Meet me in the nocturnal house in 15 minutes.
别误会  我不喜欢跟别的男人那样约会
Uhh, hey look, I don't really enjoy being with other men that way.
要动物园礼券吗
But, um, zoo dollars?
是说你猴子的事
It's about your monkey.
它还没死
It's alive.
我不懂  你为什么不救他
I don't understand, why didn't you help that man?
因为我是神经外科医生
Uhh, cause, uhh, I'm a neurosurgeon
他显然是患了  食道阻塞症
and that was clearly a case of, uh, uh, foodal chokage.
好吧  听着  我要告诉你一件事
Alright, look, I got to tell you something.
别别别  你什么都不用告诉我
No, no no no, you don't have to tell me anything.
你不用向我作解释
You don't have to explain yourself to me.
我有什么权利质疑伟大的德雷克·拉莫雷医生
Ooh, who am I to question the great Dr. Drake Remore?
-能接近你  我就该满足了  -嘿  我...
- I should just be happy to be near you. - Hey I-
嘿什么
Hey what?
就只是"嘿"一声
That's it, just hey.
像舞曲结束时  要喊"嘿"
Like at the end of a dance, HEY!
有一天你们会长大  你们会想跟别人上床
There'll be times when you get older when you'll want to sleep with people
只为搏得他们欢心  但别这样
just to make them like you... But don't.
因为那是另一件不明智的事
Cause that's another thing that you don't wanna do,
一起来
everybody!
因为那是另一件不明智的事
That's another thing that you don't wanna do.
-太棒了  -很有教育性
- Excellent! - Very informative!
一点也没有少儿不宜
Not at all inappropriate!
谢谢各位光临  后面有饼干  自己去拿
Thank you for coming everybody. There're cookies in the back.
表演很精彩  孩子们爱死你了
That was great, the kids loved you.
我酷毙了
Yay, I rock.
知道为什么吗
And you know why?
因为你实话实说  从来没人对小孩子说实话
Because you told the truth, and nobody ever tells kids the truth.
你真了不得
You were incredible.
但是呢
But.
你怎么知道还有但是
How did you know there was a but?
我直觉很灵敏  不是坏话就是好话
I sense these things. It was either but or butter.
问题是  我觉得有些父母
The thing is, I think some of the parents,
会希望你多唱一点儿童歌曲  比如...
they were kinda hopin' that you'd play more songs about like,
农场小动物们
barnyard animals.
我可以啊
I can do that.
-真的吗  -是的
- Really? - Yeah.
因为那样就再好不过了
Because that would be fantastic.
怎么  你要亲我吗
What? You wanna kiss me?
有这想法
Thinkin' about it.
蝙蝠  黑暗世界的大使
Ahh, the bat. Ambassador of darkness,
像一只插翅的信差冲出巢穴
flitting out of his cave like a winged messenger,
死神的盲目幽灵
sightless spectre of the macabe.
-兄弟  我的猴子呢  -对了
- Buddy, my monkey? - Oh, yeah, right.
几个月前  这里被洗劫  内贼干的
There was a break-in, few months back, inside job.
你的猴子被偷了
Your monkey was taken.
我的天  可是动物园说我的猴子死了
Oh my God. But the zoo told me that my monkey was dead.
动物园  动物园说什么你都信吗
The zoo! Do you believe everything the zoo tells ya?
动物园只是告诉过我这件事
That, that's the only thing the zoo's ever told me.
他们当然会说它死了  他们怕传出去影响不好
Of course they're gonna say he's dead. They don't want the bad publicity.
他们掩饰得密不透风
It's all a great big cover-up.
你知道这件事情都牵涉到哪级高层了吗
Do you have any idea how high up this thing goes?
那个利普森吗
That guy Lipson?
利普森也知情
Lipson knows.
利普森也知情?
Lipson knows huh?
你好  负鼠先生
Ahh, hello Mr. Opossum,
万树之谜  上下颠倒的夜之民
enigma of the trees, upside-down denizen of the night,
-嘲弄着地心引力...  -兄弟  我的猴子呢
- taunting gravity with... - Buddy, my monkey, my monkey.
小道消息
Word on the street
当我说"小道"的时候
well, when I say street,
-我指的是园里的仿真小道  -当然了
- I mean those little pretend streets they have here at the zoo. - Of course.
你的猴子已经进入演艺圈了
Your monkey found a new career, in the entertainment field.
我只知道这一些
That's all I know.
怎么可能
This is unbelievable.
那你说  这条消息对你值多少钱  朋友
So, what is this information worth to you, my friend?
你是暗示我要贿赂你吗
Are you trying to get me to bribe you?
或许吧
Maybe.
可是你都已经告诉我了
But you already told me everything.
你们看  马塞尔就是"猴子乐"广告里的那只猴子
Check it out, he actually is the Monkey Shine monkey.
那你打算怎么办
Well, so what're you gonna do?
我要打电话给那家啤酒公司  问它的去向
Well, I guess I'm gonna call the beer company and try to find out where he is.
我丢了克莱兹代尔马时就是这么做的
That's what I did when I lost my Clydesdales.
-你们好  -菲比好
- OK, hi again. - Hi Phoebe.
今天我要先唱些农场动物的歌曲
Today we're gonna start with some songs about barnyard animals.
牧场奶牛哞哞叫  牧场奶牛哞哞叫
Oh, the cow in the meadow goes moo, Oh, the cow in the meadow goes moo.
农夫敲破它的头  然后再剁成肉酱
Then the farmer hits him on the head and grinds him up,
于是就有了汉堡
And that's how we get hamburgers.
轮到小鸡仔了
Nooowww, chickens!
德雷克  你是唯一救得了她的人
You're the only one who can save her, Drake.
该死  我是医生  不是神
Damn it, I'm a doctor, I'm not God.
我的信仰就是这样被推翻了的
Well, there goes my whole belief system.
我是艾丽卡
It's Erica.
老天  快  关掉电视
Oh my God, quick turn off the TV.
不不不  等等  我要看结果
No no no, wait, I wanna see what happens.
我救醒了莱斯利  然后我们亲热了
Uh, I get Leslie out of the coma and then we make out.
怎么可能  你刚还在亲塞布丽娜
Well how can that be, you were just kissing Sabrina?
瑞秋  在那个世界里  乔伊可是神经外科医生
Rachel, it's a world where Joey is a neuro-surgeon.
艾丽卡  快进来
Hey Erica, c'mon in.
你怎么这么快就到了  我刚还看到你在赛伦
How did you get here so fast, I just saw you in Salem?
对  他们用直升机送我  什么事
Right, they uh, they choppered  me in. What's up?
你还在这里开上小派对了  她在吗
Ohh, and I see you're having a little party, too. Is she here, huh, huh?
谁
Who?
塞布丽娜  你们的事我都知道了
Sabrina. I know about you two.
我看到你们两个在医生休息室里接吻
I saw you today kissing in the doctor's lounge.
不是你想的那样  当时...
It's not what you think, that was...
你还说你只爱我一个
You told me I was the only one.
好  听着  够了
Alright look, that's it.
我们还是别再见面了
I don't think we should see each other anymore, alright?
我知道我很久以前就应该告诉你了
Look, I know I should have told you this a long time ago
我并不是德雷克·拉莫雷
but I am not Drake Remore, OK?
我连医生都不是  我是个演员
I'm not even a doctor, I'm an actor.
我只是假装我是医生而已
I just pretend to be a doctor.
天呐  那医院的人知道吗
Oh my God. Do the people at the hospital know about this?
你们谁来帮我解个围
Somebody wanna help me out here?
我有办法  我有办法
Oh, I know, I know.
我在哪里
Where am I?
大学的附设医院
University hospital.
你已经在这里躺了十八年
Same place you have been in the hospital for 18 years
你怎么能同时出现在两个地方
How, how can you be here and there.
因为那是电视节目
'Cause it's a television show.
德雷克  你到底要说什么
Drake, what're you getting at?
我不是德雷克
I'm not Drake.
没错  他不是德雷克
That's right, he's not Drake,
他是汉斯·拉莫雷  德雷克的邪恶双胞胎弟弟
he's Hans Remore, Drake's evil twin.
真的吗
Is this true?
是的  是真的
Yes, yes, it is this true.
我知道因为
And I know this because,
他装作德雷克来骗我上床
because he pretended to be Drake to, to sleep with me.
然后他告诉我  他要带我私奔  他骗我
And then he told me he would run away with me, and he didn't.
然后你马桶盖没有放下来  你这个浑蛋
And you left the toilet seat up, you bastard.
这些都是真的吗
Is all this true?
是  恐怕是真的
Yes, I'm afraid it is.
我根本配不上你  艾丽卡
You deserve much better than me Erica.
你应该跟真正的德雷克在一起  你爱上的人是他
You deserve to be with the real Drake, he's the one you fell in love with.
去赛伦找他吧  他才是你的王子
Go to Salem, find him, he's the guy for you.
汉斯
Oh Hans.
汉斯  汉斯
Hans...Hans...
邪恶的双胞胎弟弟
You evil twin.
对  再见  艾丽卡
Right. Goodbye Erica,
一路顺风
good luck in Salem.
保重
Take care.
我永远不会忘记你的  汉斯
I'll never forget you, Hans.
该算账了  你们竟然对我泼水
OK, alright, the people who threw the water.
我们都是在帮你解围
Helping you out!
开除我  为什么
Fired! Why?
很多父母向图书馆的董事会投诉
The library board has had a lot of complaints from parents about
你歌词里的不当内容
some of the stuff in your songs.
太扯了吧
I can't believe it.
你没告诉你的董事会
Did you tell your board
孩子们多想听实话吗
about how kids want to hear the truth?
没
No.
我懂了
I see.
你要是只唱一些常规的儿歌就好了
Maybe if you just played some regular kiddie songs.
不  你想让我当什么呢
No. What do you, what do you want me to be,
愚蠢的紫色大恐龙吗
like some stupid, big, like, purple dinosaur?
-我又没说你必须当巴尼  -巴尼是谁
- I'm not saying you have to be Barney. - Who's Barney.
我查到了马塞尔的下落
Well, I tracked down Marcel and get this,
他现在健康快乐
he's healthy,  he's happy,
它在纽约拍《恐怖地带之病毒肆虐曼哈顿》
and he's right here in New York filming Outbreak II - The Virus Takes Manhattan.
不是吧  天呐
You're kidding. Oh, my god.
-太神了  -我知道
- This is amazing. - I know.
我才终于混上电视  而这猴子已经开始拍电影了
I finally get a part on TV and the monkey's makin' movies.
-瑞秋  我好了  -好的
- OK, Rachel, I'm ready. - OK.
请问  那个说实话的歌手是在这里吗
Excuse me. Is this where the singing lady is who tells the truth?
对  我猜是我
Um, yeah, I guess that's me.
她在这里
She's here.
有时男人爱女人
Sometimes men love women,
有时男人爱男人
sometimes men love men,
然后还有双性恋
and then there are bisexuals,
虽然有些说他们在骗自己
though some just say they're kidding themselves.
我好激动  我都快一年没见到我的猴子了
This is so exciting, I haven't seen my monkey in almost a year.
你洗澡从来不往下看吗  拜托
What, you never look down in the shower? Oh please.
我连说个猴子等于命根子的笑话都不可以吗
I'm not allowed to make one joke in the monkey-is-penis genre?
快  快  各位  往后退  快快快
C'mon people, back up please, back up, c'mon, c'mon, c'mon, c'mon.
请问  那只猴子在哪里
Uh, excuse me, uh, where can we find the monkey?
抱歉  各位  这场戏不对外开放
I'm sorry guys, closed set.
对不起  你不明白
Uh, I'm sorry, you don't understand,
我是它的朋友  我们以前住在一起
I'm, I'm, I'm a friend of his. We uh, we used to live together.
我跟海豚飞宝还在博卡诺斯合租过呢
Yeah, and I have a time share in the Pocanos with Flipper.
罗斯  它在那里
Ross, there he is.
兄弟  马塞尔  马塞尔
Hey, hey buddy, Marcel. Marcel.
在丛林里  偌大的丛林
In the jungle, the mighty jungle
今夜狮子睡着了
the lion sleeps tonight.
在丛林里  偌大的丛林
In the jungle, the mighty jungle,
今夜狮子睡着了
the lion sleeps tonight.
他们不带你去看兽医
They won't take you to the vet,
你不是他们最爱的宠物
you are obviously not their favorite pet.
臭猫咪  臭猫咪
Smelly cat. Smelly cat.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
-怎么了  -对不起
- What? - I'm sorry.
为什么要道歉
What's wrong with that?
我应该挑首硬汉点的歌给你
I think you might want to pick a more masculine note.